<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Ronny Munene</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Ronny Munene</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ronny Munene</title>
      <url>//localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>//localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.139.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CodeHatari Blogging Hub</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/projects/software-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/projects/software-engineering/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CodeHatari Blogging Hub is a platform designed to help developers share their knowledge, tutorials, and tips through blogging. Features user authentication and a responsive design. Integrates NewsAPI to provide users with the latest news articles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;technology-and-architecture&#34;&gt;Technology and Architecture&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;frontend&#34;&gt;Frontend&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vue.js 3: Used to building dynamic and responsive user interfaces. Vue&amp;rsquo;s reactivity system allows for seamless data binding and component-based architecture.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nuxt.js: A framework built on top of Vue.js provides server-side rendering, static site generation, and a powerful configuration-based structure for efficient development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;backend&#34;&gt;Backend&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FastAPI: Used it to build APIs with Python 3.10. We chose FastAPI because it ensures rapid development and high performance, making it an excellent choice for API development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SQLAlchemy: Used it to handle database operations providing a powerful and flexible database management solution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;intergration&#34;&gt;Intergration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Integrated &lt;code&gt;NewsAPI&lt;/code&gt; into the blog pages to provide users with the latest news articles, enriching the blog content and ensuring up-to-date information is available.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solubility Predictor using Machine Learning</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/projects/machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/projects/machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project delves into the realm of cheminformatics to predict the aqueous solubility of chemical compounds using machine learning techniques. By leveraging a comprehensive dataset containing molecular descriptors from &lt;a href=&#34;&#39;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dataprofessor/data/master/delaney_solubility_with_descriptors.csv&#39;&#34;&gt;Delaney&amp;rsquo;s solubility dataset&lt;/a&gt;, I explored key molecular properties like molecular weight, LogP, and the number of rotatable bonds, transforming raw chemical data into actionable predictive models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data Analysis: I meticulously prepared the dataset by separating the target variable (logS, which represents solubility) from the features (molecular descriptors). I then split the data into training and testing sets to ensure unbiased model evaluation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starlink customer sentiment analysis</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/projects/machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/projects/machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this project, I performed sentiment analysis on customer reviews of Starlink products sourced from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jumia.co.ke/catalog/productratingsreviews/sku/BR269EA1PRKULNAFAMZ/&#34;&gt;Jumia&lt;/a&gt;, an e-commerce platform in Kenya. By extracting, cleaning, and analyzing the reviews using Python, I transformed raw customer feedback into actionable insights, highlighting key strengths and areas for improvement. The analysis involved natural language processing (NLP) techniques, data visualization, and word cloud generation to summarize customer sentiment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tools-and-libraries-used&#34;&gt;Tools and Libraries Used:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programming Language: Python
Libraries: requests, &lt;code&gt;BeautifulSoup&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;pandas&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;nltk&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;matplotlib&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;seaborn&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;TextBlob&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;wordcloud&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;csv&lt;/code&gt;
Key Tasks and Insights:
Data Extraction and Cleaning:
I scraped reviews from multiple pages of Jumia using &lt;code&gt;BeautifulSoup&lt;/code&gt; and saved the data into a CSV file for further analysis. The text was preprocessed by removing unwanted characters and stopwords to improve sentiment accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World Carbon Emission Dashboard using Panel</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/projects/data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/projects/data-science/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project focuses on developing an interactive CO2 Emission Dashboard using Python and the &lt;code&gt;Panel&lt;/code&gt; library. It allows users to explore global CO2 emissions from 1750 to 2021, segmented by continent and specific sources like coal, oil, and gas. The dashboard includes visualizations like &lt;code&gt;line charts&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;scatterplots&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;bar charts&lt;/code&gt; , along with interactive widgets for real-time data exploration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data Preparation: I imported and cleaned CO2 emissions data, filling missing values and creating additional columns like GDP per capita to enrich the dataset for better analysis. I ensured data accuracy by processing and grouping it based on countries, continents, and years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>YouTube Global Data Analysis</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/projects/data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/projects/data-science/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this project, I dove deep into YouTube&amp;rsquo;s vast global dataset to uncover trends and insights that shape the platform’s success across continents. By leveraging a comprehensive dataset from &lt;code&gt;Kaggle&lt;/code&gt; , I explored key metrics like uploads, views, subscriber counts, and estimated earnings, transforming raw data into actionable insights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continental Insights: I aggregated data to compare YouTube&amp;rsquo;s performance across continents, analyzing total subscribers, uploads, views, earnings, and the number of active content creators per region. This helped highlight regional disparities and dominant markets.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
