<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Ronny Munene</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ronny Munene</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ronny Munene</title>
      <url>//localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>//localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.139.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Data Science</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/blogs/unraveling-the-power-of-datadata-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/blogs/unraveling-the-power-of-datadata-101/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;preview&#34;&gt;Preview&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;unraveling-the-power-of-data-data-101&#34;&gt;Unraveling the Power of Data. (Data 101)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data science is an interdisciplinary field that transforms raw data into actionable insights, playing a crucial role in informed decision-making, predictive analytics, and enhancing customer understanding across various industries. It encompasses diverse career paths, including Data Analyst, Data Scientist, and Machine Learning Engineer, requiring a blend of technical skills like programming in Python and SQL, as well as soft skills such as critical thinking and effective communication.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Infographics</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/infographics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 23:15:00 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/infographics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I also create hand-drawn infographics and illustrations to summarize the key concepts in data science, machine learning and bioinformatics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What happens when you type google.com in your browser and press Enter</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/blogs/unveiling-the-digital-symphony/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 23:15:00 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/blogs/unveiling-the-digital-symphony/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;preview&#34;&gt;Preview&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;behind-the-scenes-of-your-simple-search-unveiling-the-digital-symphony&#34;&gt;Behind the Scenes of Your Simple Search: Unveiling the Digital Symphony&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever paused to consider the complex web of technologies that brings your favorite websites to life with just a click? In this captivating blog post, we take you on a thrilling journey through the intricate processes that occur when you type &amp;ldquo;google.com&amp;rdquo; into your browser and hit Enter. From the silent yet powerful DNS requests that translate user-friendly URLs into machine-readable IP addresses to the sophisticated load balancers that ensure seamless access even during peak traffic, every step is a testament to the ingenuity of modern internet infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My 1st post</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/page/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/page/</guid>
      <description>Desc Text.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello World! I’m Ronny Munene, a dedicated software engineer with a profound passion for data science and computer science, committed to designing cutting-edge systems and software. As an enthusiastic developer and data science advocate, I thrive on leveraging technology to tackle contemporary challenges, with a vision of shaping a brighter future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My robust foundation in both theoretical concepts and practical applications equips me with a unique skill set, enabling me to approach complex problems from diverse angles and develop innovative solutions. I am excited to contribute my expertise to impactful projects that drive progress and transformation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CodeHatari Blogging Hub</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/projects/software-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/projects/software-engineering/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CodeHatari Blogging Hub is a platform designed to help developers share their knowledge, tutorials, and tips through blogging. Features user authentication and a responsive design. Integrates NewsAPI to provide users with the latest news articles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;technology-and-architecture&#34;&gt;Technology and Architecture&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;frontend&#34;&gt;Frontend&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vue.js 3: Used to building dynamic and responsive user interfaces. Vue&amp;rsquo;s reactivity system allows for seamless data binding and component-based architecture.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nuxt.js: A framework built on top of Vue.js provides server-side rendering, static site generation, and a powerful configuration-based structure for efficient development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;backend&#34;&gt;Backend&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FastAPI: Used it to build APIs with Python 3.10. We chose FastAPI because it ensures rapid development and high performance, making it an excellent choice for API development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SQLAlchemy: Used it to handle database operations providing a powerful and flexible database management solution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;intergration&#34;&gt;Intergration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Integrated &lt;code&gt;NewsAPI&lt;/code&gt; into the blog pages to provide users with the latest news articles, enriching the blog content and ensuring up-to-date information is available.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solubility Predictor using Machine Learning</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/projects/machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/projects/machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project delves into the realm of cheminformatics to predict the aqueous solubility of chemical compounds using machine learning techniques. By leveraging a comprehensive dataset containing molecular descriptors from &lt;a href=&#34;&#39;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dataprofessor/data/master/delaney_solubility_with_descriptors.csv&#39;&#34;&gt;Delaney&amp;rsquo;s solubility dataset&lt;/a&gt;, I explored key molecular properties like molecular weight, LogP, and the number of rotatable bonds, transforming raw chemical data into actionable predictive models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data Analysis: I meticulously prepared the dataset by separating the target variable (logS, which represents solubility) from the features (molecular descriptors). I then split the data into training and testing sets to ensure unbiased model evaluation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starlink customer sentiment analysis</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/projects/machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/projects/machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this project, I performed sentiment analysis on customer reviews of Starlink products sourced from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jumia.co.ke/catalog/productratingsreviews/sku/BR269EA1PRKULNAFAMZ/&#34;&gt;Jumia&lt;/a&gt;, an e-commerce platform in Kenya. By extracting, cleaning, and analyzing the reviews using Python, I transformed raw customer feedback into actionable insights, highlighting key strengths and areas for improvement. The analysis involved natural language processing (NLP) techniques, data visualization, and word cloud generation to summarize customer sentiment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tools-and-libraries-used&#34;&gt;Tools and Libraries Used:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programming Language: Python
Libraries: requests, &lt;code&gt;BeautifulSoup&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;pandas&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;nltk&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;matplotlib&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;seaborn&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;TextBlob&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;wordcloud&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;csv&lt;/code&gt;
Key Tasks and Insights:
Data Extraction and Cleaning:
I scraped reviews from multiple pages of Jumia using &lt;code&gt;BeautifulSoup&lt;/code&gt; and saved the data into a CSV file for further analysis. The text was preprocessed by removing unwanted characters and stopwords to improve sentiment accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World Carbon Emission Dashboard using Panel</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/projects/data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/projects/data-science/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project focuses on developing an interactive CO2 Emission Dashboard using Python and the &lt;code&gt;Panel&lt;/code&gt; library. It allows users to explore global CO2 emissions from 1750 to 2021, segmented by continent and specific sources like coal, oil, and gas. The dashboard includes visualizations like &lt;code&gt;line charts&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;scatterplots&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;bar charts&lt;/code&gt; , along with interactive widgets for real-time data exploration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data Preparation: I imported and cleaned CO2 emissions data, filling missing values and creating additional columns like GDP per capita to enrich the dataset for better analysis. I ensured data accuracy by processing and grouping it based on countries, continents, and years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>YouTube Global Data Analysis</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/projects/data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/projects/data-science/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this project, I dove deep into YouTube&amp;rsquo;s vast global dataset to uncover trends and insights that shape the platform’s success across continents. By leveraging a comprehensive dataset from &lt;code&gt;Kaggle&lt;/code&gt; , I explored key metrics like uploads, views, subscriber counts, and estimated earnings, transforming raw data into actionable insights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continental Insights: I aggregated data to compare YouTube&amp;rsquo;s performance across continents, analyzing total subscribers, uploads, views, earnings, and the number of active content creators per region. This helped highlight regional disparities and dominant markets.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
